"There's no place like home" This English saying has much truth in it: the best place to be is surrounded by our treasured possessions and our loved ones and with a roof over our head.
“金窝银窝不如自己的狗窝”，这句英语谚语说得很有道理：最好的地方莫过于在可以遮风挡雨的家里，和珍爱的物品、挚爱的亲人在一起。
And for many young adults, it's the only affordable place to stay; somewhere where they can receive first-class service from mum and dad.
对于许多年轻人来说，家也是唯一住得起的地方——在这里，他们能享受到父母无微不至的“头等舱”服务。
But this comes at a price!
但这份安逸，也是要付出代价的！
In some countries, it's quite traditional for people in their late teens and early 20s to live at home with their parents, but in other places, flying the nest to start their own independent life is very desirable.
在一些国家，十八九岁到二十出头的年轻人和父母同住是一种传统，但在另一些地方，年轻人更向往“离巢”，开启独立的生活。
There is no nagging, and you can come and go as you wish.
那样的生活没有父母的唠叨，还能随心所欲自由出入。
But there's been a growing trend, in the UK at least, for young people to return home to live - or not to leave home at all.
但至少在英国，一种相反的趋势正在升温：越来越多的年轻人选择搬回家住，或是干脆从未离开过家。
According to the UK's Office for National Statistics, about a quarter of young adults aged 20-34 live at home, and that figure has been growing.
英国国家统计局的数据显示，在20至34岁的年轻人中，约有四分之一的人仍与父母同住，且这一比例还在持续上升。
A survey by a price comparison website found that 18% of adult children in the UK said they were moving back home because of debt, compared with 8% last year.
一家比价网站的调查显示，英国有18%的成年子女表示，他们因为负债而搬回父母家居住，而去年这一比例仅为8%。
More young people had lost their jobs, and others couldn't afford their rent compared with the previous year.
与往年相比，更多年轻人失业，还有一些人负担不起房租。
So, it's easy to see why they're increasingly becoming home birds.
如此一来，他们越来越恋家的原因就显而易见了。
The BBC's Lucy Hooker explains that many returning adult children enjoy home comforts.
英国广播公司的露西·胡克解释道，许多搬回家住的成年子女，都很享受家里的舒适便利。
These include cooked meals, a full fridge and cleaning, as well as their bills being covered by what is commonly called "the hotel of mum and dad".
这些福利包括现成的饭菜、满满当当的冰箱、有人帮忙打扫卫生，还有各种账单都由被戏称为“爸妈旅馆”的家来承担。
But for the "hoteliers", that's mum and dad, the survey found the average cost to them has gone up sharply, and that they are sacrificing luxuries and holidays to look after their "big kids".
但“旅馆”的经营者——也就是父母们，却为此付出了高昂的代价。
Emma Craig from Moneysupermarket says "they're trying to look after their children more.
调查发现，父母的平均支出大幅增加，他们不得不放弃奢侈品和度假机会，来照顾这些“大孩子”。
If your child comes home and you see them struggling financially, you feel more awkward asking them for rent or to contribute.
来自省钱网站的艾玛·克雷格表示：“父母总想多照顾孩子一些。
It tugs on your heartstrings more."
如果看到回家的孩子经济拮据，你会更不好意思向他们要房租或让他们分担开支，这更会牵动为人父母的心弦。”
With parents splashing out around £1,886 on takeaway food, buying new furniture and upgrading their Wi-Fi for the benefit of their offspring, it's easy for the returning children to put their feet up and make themselves at home.
父母们为了子女，斥资约1886英镑用于购买外卖食品、添置新家具和升级无线网络。有了这些支持，搬回家的子女们自然能舒舒服服地放松休息，毫无拘束地享受家的温暖。
That's before they learn a home truth – that one day it might be their own kids who'll be checking into the hotel of mum and dad!
不过，他们迟早会明白一个令人不快的事实——或许有一天，住进“爸妈旅馆”的，会是他们自己的孩子！